Henry F. Dobyns Papers 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Henry F. Dobyns Papers, 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000)
MS 461
Dobyns, Henry F.
Papers, 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000). This collection is comprised of the papers of anthropologist Henry F. Dobyns. The bulk of the material relates to his professional career as an anthropologist and ethnohistorian. Items includes correspondence, published and unpublished writings, research material and manuscripts related to the Gila River Indian Community water rights cases, the Cornell Peru Project and the Hualapai Tribal Nation, academic and professional material as well as photographic and audio visual material.
490 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
Access to Series II: Correspondence Box 23, Folders 19-28 are restricted until 2029.
All materials related to the Hualapai Tribal Nation are restricted including materials from Series III Writings boxes 39 folder 12, 43 folder 2, 51 folder 12, and 61 folder 3, Series VI Academic Files boxes 205 folder 15 and 207 folders 9, 17-31, Series VIII Hualapai Tribal Nation Files boxes 221 folders 30-37, boxes 222-223, Series IX Research files box 226, box 227 folders 1-7, box 228 folder 1, Series X: Index Cards Files boxes 243-255, 325, 366, 449, 451, 455, Series XI: Photographic Material box 464 folders 21-29, box 465 folders 1-5, boxes 473, 477 and Series XII: Audio Material box 481 folders 1-14, 16-32, 46-47, 51, box 482 folders 4-6, 8-14, 16, 19-20, 24. Please contact Special Collections at LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu for information about access to these materials.
Biographical Note
Henry Farmer Dobyns, Jr. was born in Tucson, Arizona on July 3, 1925 to Henry F and Susie Kell (Comstock) Dobyns but spent most of his childhood in Casa Grande, Arizona. After graduating from Casa Grande Union High School he entered the U.S. Army in 1943 but spent most of his service in the hospital after contracting rheumatic fever. Following his service he attended the University of Arizona where he received a Bachelor of Arts Degree in Anthropology in 1949 as well as a Master of Arts Degree in Anthropology in 1956. In 1948 he married Zipporah Pottenger and had four children, Rique, Bill, Maritha and Mark. From 1949 to 1952 he acted as an instructor at Cornell University’s Field Laboratory in Applied Anthropology in Arizona and New Mexico. While a graduate student he began his prolific publishing career, winning the Bronislaw Malinowski Award from the Society of Applied Anthropology in 1951 for his article Blunders with Bolsas.
Dobyns began working with Native American tribes on land claims and water rights case as a graduate student at the University of Arizona in 1952, work he continued for 50 years with various tribes. From 1952 to 1956, along with Robert Euler, he gathered ethnohistorical and archaeological evidence for the Hualapai Tribal Nation’s land claims case and acted as an expert witness before the U.S. Supreme Court with much of the information in his M.A. thesis being used in the Indian Claims Commission hearings. He also spent three decades working as a consultant for the Gila River Indian Community in their litigation over water rights.
Dobyns received many fellowships in support of his research including the National Science Foundation fellowship from 1956-1957 and the Social Science Research Council fellowship in 1959 before receiving his Doctorate in Anthropology from Cornell University in 1960. He joined the Cornell Peru Project in 1960 where he worked in a number of positions including research coordinator from 1960-1962, Peace Corps coordinator from 1962-1964, coordinator of the Comparative Studies of Cultural Change program as well as the Coordinator of the Andean Indian Community Research and Development project from 1963-1966 and finally the Associate Director of the Cornell Peru Project before becoming Director of the project following the death of the former director, Allan Holmberg. Dr. Dobyns married his second wife, anthropologist Dr. Cara Richards in 1958 and had one child, York Dobyns. In 1968 Dr. Dobyns married his third wife Mary Faith Patterson.
Dobyns taught at a variety of institutions over his long academic career. In 1966 Dr. Dobyns became the Chairman of the Department of Anthropology at the University of Kentucky. He joined the staff of Prescott College, Center of Man and Environment in 1970 as a professor and later as the Vice-president for Academic Affairs. He also taught at the University of Florida-Gainesville (1977-1979), University of Wisconsin-Parkside (1974-1977, 1983-1984) and the University of Oklahoma (1989). He also worked as a senior researcher at the Bureau of Applied Research in Anthropology at the University of Arizona and on projects for the National Park Service. From 1971 to 1976 Dr. Dobyns edited the Indian Tribal Series, a 40 volume series of tribal history and culture of which Dobyns wrote six volumes.
Dobyns was a National Endowment for the Humanities research fellow at the Newberry Library in Chicago and in 1983 he directed a seminar on Native American Historical Demography also funded by the NEH. In the 1980s and 1990s he returned to the Newberry Library each summer to contribute to the NEH Summer Institute in Native American Literature.
Dobyns was a prolific author who conducted extensive research. He may be best known for his work in historical demography including the article Estimating Aboriginal American Population: An Appraisal of Techniques with a New Hemispheric Estimate (1966). A few of his other works including Papagos in the Cotton Fields (1951), The Ghost Dance of 1889 among the Pai Indians of Northwestern Arizona (1967), Spanish Colonial Tucson: A Demographic History (1976), Indians of the Southwest: A Critical Bibliography (1980), From Fire to Flood: Historic Human Destruction of Sonoran Desert Riverine (1981), and Their Number Become Thinned (1983). Henry F. Dobyns died June 21, 2009.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 13 series (and 37 subseries)
Series I: Personal Files 1890-2003
Series II: Correspondence 1918-2008
Series III: Writings 1947-2009
Subseries 1: Manuscripts 1947-2009
Subseries 2: Articles 1948-2004
Subseries 3: Reports 1950-2008
Subseries 4: Book Reviews 1959-2008
Subseries 5: Speeches 1952-2005
Subseries 6: Publicity Files 1966-2002
Subseries 7: Miscellaneous 1950-2008
Series IV: Gila River Indian Community Files 1732-2004
Subseries 1: Correspondence 1963-2004
Subseries 2: Reports 1974-2002
Subseries 3: Case and Research Files 1732-2003
Subseries 4: Miscellaneous 1974-2004
Series V: Cornell Peru Project Files 1943-1980
Subseries 1: Writings 1946-1976
Subseries 2: Administrative Files 1948-1980
Subseries 3: Research Data Files 1960-1969
Subseries 4: Research Files 1943-1968
Series VI: Academic Files 1947-1997
Subseries 1: Cornell University 1951-1966
Subseries 2: Newberry Library 1978-1997
Subseries 3: Prescott College 1960-1977
Subseries 4: University of Florida- Gainesville 1972-1980
Subseries 5: University of Kentucky 1947-1970
Subseries 6: University of Oklahoma 1989
Subseries 7: University of Wisconsin- Parkside 1972-1983
Series VII: Activity Files 1947-2001
Subseries 1: American Society for Ethnohistory 1962-2001
Subseries 2: Anza Trail 2008-2009
Subseries 3: Casa Grande Valley Historical Society 1975-2002
Subseries 4: Conferences 1947-2000
Subseries 5: Cultural Systems Research Inc 1978
Subseries 6: Organization of American States 1975-1976
Subseries 7: Piñon Press 1977-1986
Subseries 8: Tohono O’odham Nation Files 1937-1977
Series VIII: Hualapai Tribal Nation Files 1897-1986
Series IX: Research Files 1947-2009
Series X: Index Cards Files ca. 1950-2008
Series XI: Photographic Material 1932-2000
Subseries 1: Photograph Albums 1943-1944
Subseries 2: Photographs 1932-2000
Subseries 3: Negatives 1942-1988
Subseries 4: Slides 1948-1985
Series XII: Audiovisual Material 1937-2001
Subseries 1: Audio and video recordings 1937-1978
Subseries 2: Computer Disks 1989-2001
Subseries 3: Microfilm undated
Series XIII: Oversize Material 1764-1996
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000). This collection consists of the papers of Henry F. Dobyns relating to his professional career as an anthropologist and ethnohistorian. The bulk of the material includes Dobyns’ extensive writings as well as manuscripts and research materials related to his work on the Cornell Peru Project and with the Gila River Indian community. Also included is correspondence, research material such as copies of archival research, field notebooks, news clippings and notes, academic material such as administrative and teaching material and material related to his professional career as well as photographic material which includes personal photographic albums and photographs, negatives and slides primarily related to his work in South America and with Native American tribes. Index card files containing research notes, book and articles citations and news clipping are also included. This collection contains material in Spanish. This collection also contains books and maps that can be found in the University of Arizona catalog under Henry F. Dobyns Library.
Henry F. Dobyns collections can also be found at Cornell University and the Arizona Historical Society.
Cornell Vicos Collection, University Archives/Vicos, Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Henry F. Dobyns papers, #6803. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Dobyns papers, 1950-1993. MS 0221. Arizona Historical Society. Tucson.
Access Terms
Dobyns, Henry F, -- Archives.
Cornell Peru Project.
Ethnohistory -- Arizona.
Indians of North America--Arizona.
Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Arizona.
Gila River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community -- Trials, litigation, etc.
Hualapai Indian Tribe of the Hualapai Indian Reservation, Arizona -- Trials, litigation, etc.
Tohono O'odham Indians.
Hualapai Indians.
Indians of North America -- Southwest, New.
Water rights--Arizona.
American Society for Ethnohistory.
Prescott College (Prescott, Ariz.).
United States -- Trials, litigation, etc.
Vicos (Peru).
Container List
- Series I: Personal Files, 1890-2003
  This series contains personal material associated with Henry F. Dobyns. It includes biographical materials, certificates and class material from both his high school and University of Arizona undergraduate educations as well as some material related to his parents, Henry F. and Susie Dobyns.
  - Archaeological excavations, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical sketches, 1983, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Calendars, 1964, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendars, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Calendars, 1972-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Casa Grande Union High School- Problems of Democracy, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Casa Grande Union High School- Social Hygiene, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Certificates, 1941-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cougar Growl, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diaries, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dobyns, Henry F. Sr., 1936-1939, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dobyns, Susie C., 1905-1953, undated (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Dobyns, William H., 1890-1895 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Family trees, 1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Financial ledgers, 1940, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Financial ledgers, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Financial ledgers, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Financial ledgers, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Financial ledgers, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Financial ledgers, 1964, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Funeral- Thomas A. Segundo, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - High School event flyers, 1917-1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Military records, 1943-1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1925-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Personal writings, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Poetry, 1944-1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Professional record, 1942-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Programs- Annual Papago Indian Rodeo and Arts and Crafts Exhibit, 1949-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - School assignments, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Sentinal, 1928, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 1a and 1b, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 2, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 20a, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 20b, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 100, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 109a and 109b, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 115a, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 130a, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 135a, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 140a, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 140b, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 170a, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 222, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 295b, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 299b and 203, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology 642, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology club, 1947-1948, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- American Civil Liberties Union Quarterly, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- American Council on Race Relations, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- American Library Service, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - University of Arizona - Anthropology Honors- Arizona Committee on Civic Unity, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Checklist of Some Techniques Minority Improvement, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Congress of Racial Equity, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Council on Arizona Indians, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Early Man in the Americas, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Indian Action Agencies, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Institute for American Democracy, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Southern Regional Council, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- State Minority Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - University of Arizona- Anthropology Honors- Unsuccessful and to hold replies, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - University of Arizona-The Atlatl, 1946-1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - University of Arizona- Botany 1-c, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - University of Arizona- Business Administration 11-c, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - University of Arizona- English 1a-e, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - University of Arizona- English 6-c, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - University of Arizona- English 104a-c, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - University of Arizona- English 142, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - University of Arizona- English 185, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - University of Arizona- Folklore committee, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - University of Arizona- Geology 1a and 1b, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - University of Arizona- History 11-c and 12-c, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - University of Arizona- History 128s, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - University of Arizona- History 130a, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - University of Arizona- Introduction to Humanities, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - University of Arizona- Master’s Comprehensive Examination, 1948, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - University of Arizona- Miscellaneous, 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - University of Arizona- National Government 51, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - University of Arizona- Plane Trigonometry, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - University of Arizona- Southwestern Indians, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - University of Arizona- Spanish 3a-1c and 2c, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - University of Arizona- State and Local Government 62, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - University of Arizona- Unidentified class notes, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - University of Arizona- Unidentified class notes, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - University of Arizona- Unvanishing Indians, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Work logs, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Yearbooks-The Cougar, 1929-1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Yearbooks- The Cougar, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1918-2008
  This series contains correspondence from personal and professional contacts including correspondence with prominent anthropologists and ethnohistorians as well as correspondence related to various writing projects. This series is arranged alphabetically by last name or subject with items in folders arranged chronologically. Some material is in Spanish. Correspondence is also located in Series IV, V, VI, VII and VIII.
  - A, 1947-2003 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Adams, William, 1974- 1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Ad Hoc committee for Middle American Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Agency for International Development, 1967-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ahler, Stanley, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Allan, Ella May, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1954-1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - American Anthropologist, 1966-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1961-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - American Ethnological Society paper- Yuman Warfare, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - American Ethnologist, 1958, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - American Indian Culture and Research Journal, 1982-1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - American Indian Today, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - American Indian Quarterly, 1975-1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Amerind Foundation, Inc., 1958-1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Anderson, Mick, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Apache trading cards- The Indian Trader, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Apache trading cards- Perry, Edgar, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Ariss, R.M., 1956, 1958, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Arizona Academy of Science, 1957-1980 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Arizona Academy of Science, 1984-1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Arizona and the West, 1961-1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Arizona Archaeological and Historical Society, 1953-1998 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Arizona Historical Society, 1951-1972 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Arizona Historical Society, 1973-2004 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Arizona State Museum, 1958-1959, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Aubrey, John, 1981-1991, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Avery, Alec, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - B, 1959-2007 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Baird, W. David, 1972-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Baldonado, Luís, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ballena Press, 1975-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ballena Press- Blackburn, Thomas, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bancroft Library, 1953-1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Basso, Keith, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bastien, Joseph, 1987, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Baugh, Timothy, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bean, Lowell John, 1979, 1983, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Berge, Patricia, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Betley, Brian, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Blackburn, Thomas, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Blaine Ethridge Books, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Boardman, Allyne, 1961-1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Boardman, Allyne, 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Borah, Woodrow, 1967-1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Bourque, Susan, 1967-1982 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Boyd, Robert, 1982, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bradfield, Stillman, 1966-1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Brown, Richard, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Brownrigg, Leslie, 1969-1991 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Broyles, Bill, 1987, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Brugge, David, 1956-1968 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Bufkin, Donald, 1981, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1951-1980 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Bureau of Land Management, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Bushnell, Amy, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - C, 1949-2001 (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
  - Campbell, Gregory, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Cards, 1967-1986 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Cards, 1967-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Careers in Applied Anthropology article, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Casa Grande Union High School 50th Reunion, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Case Studies in Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Boyd, Robert, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Browne, Suzanne, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Euler, Robert, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Jones, Kristine, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Kessell, John, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Lovell, W. George, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Moore, John, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Morris, Richard, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Spicer, Edward, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Trimble, Michael, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Castile, George Pierre, 1982, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Chelsea House Publishers, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Chemehuevi claims case, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Childs, Thomas, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Clark, Robey, 1986, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Cohen, Lucy, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Colombian Consequences symposia, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Comstock, Waller, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Cook, James, 1986-1987, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Cook, Noble David, 1975-2002 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Cornell University, 1956-2007 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Cornell University- Wood, Deborah, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Couts Diary, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Crumrine, N. Ross, 1974-1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Crumrine, N. Ross, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Current Anthropology, 1964-1988 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Current Anthropology- Estimating Aboriginal American Population, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - D, 1956-2008 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Dallas Morning News, 1988-1989, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Danson, Edward, 1956-1977 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Davisson, Lori, 1980-1993 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Deagan, Kathleen, 1980-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Delambre, Jules, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Delgado, Carlos, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Demography of American Indians project, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Denevan, William, 1967-2006 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Desert Magazine, 1949-1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Desert Plants, 1987-1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Desert Research Institute, 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - DiPeso, Charles, 1953-1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - DiPietro, Karen, 1986-1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)